Privacy Policy | ADL                                                                        

Utility
-------

Header Social Links
-------------------

* About

* ADL Centers

* What We Do

* Resources

* Take Action

Menu

Open Global Search

Search 

Sort by RelevanceNewestOldestTitle (a-z)Title (z-a)

 Clear

Close global search

Utility
-------

Social Links
------------

Privacy Policy

==================

The Anti-Defamation League (ADL) has established this privacy policy to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this Web site: www.adl.org.

This site contains links to other sites. ADL is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site.

ADL Austria Data Protection Policy
----------------------------------

289.7 KB

#### General Information Collection and Use

ADL is the sole owner of the information collected on this site. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement. We collect information from our users at several different points on our Web site.  

#### Log Files

We use IP addresses to help us analyze trends, administer the site, track users movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use.  

#### Cookies

Our site uses 'cookies'. A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's hard drive containing information about the user. Usage of a cookie enables us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site, but is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site. If a user rejects the cookie, they may still use our site. The only drawback to this is that the user may be limited in some areas of our site (for example, certain surveys or other such activities).  

#### Various Registrations

In order to receive certain updates or use certain features of our Web site, a user may have to first complete a registration form. During registration a user is required to give their contact information (such as name and e-mail address). This information is used to contact the user about the services on our site for which they have expressed interest. If asked for, it is optional for a user to provide demographic information (such as income level and gender), and unique identifiers, but encouraged so we can provide a more personalized experience on our site and our e-mail communications with respect to content and personal topics of interest.

ADL processes its donations through a third party service. This relationship is 100% confidential and secure. After a completed donation is accepted by the third party's server and authorized, credit card information is destroyed and a finalized report is sent through to ADL. No information other than to diagnose problems with the transaction server is retained by the third party. They do not resell, retransmit, or retain any information about transactions or personal contact information for donors it processes on behalf of ADL.  

#### Newsletter

If a user wishes to subscribe to our newsletter, we ask for contact information such as name and e-mail address.  

#### Text Messaging Privacy Policy and Terms of Service and Conditions

Text messaging opt-in data and consent will not be shared with or sold to any organization. Message and data rates may apply. If you wish to unsubscribe from mobile advocacy messages, text STOP to 267-69  or click “edit subscription preferences” on your confirmation email. ADL will periodically send you advocacy and fundraising text messages. Message frequency will vary but will not exceed 10 messages per month. For help with mobile messaging, contact ADL at replies@adl.org or via our ["contact us" online form](https://www.adl.org/contact), selecting “other & general inquiries” under “topic of inquiry.” If you need help from ADL regarding an antisemitic, bias, or hate incident, please submit an [incident reporting form](https://www.adl.org/report-incident). We will work to assess your situation and respond as quickly as possible. Any personal information provided will be kept confidential consistent with local, state, and federal law. If this is an emergency, please dial 911.

ADL’s advocacy mobile messaging program is offered on an “as-is” basis. It may not be available in all areas, at all times, or on all mobile providers. You agree that neither we nor our service providers will be liable for any failed, delayed, or misdirected delivery of any mobile message or information sent through the mobile messaging program.

#### Orders

Our site uses an order form for customers to request information, products, and services. We collect visitor's contact information (such as name, e-mail, and address) and financial information (such as account or credit card numbers). Contact information from the order form is used to send information about ADL to the users of our Web site. The customer's contact information is also used to get in touch with the visitor when necessary. This information is not shared or resold in any circumstance except as may be required by law.

Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section below.

Financial information that is collected is used to bill the user for products and services. This credit card information is destroyed after a final authorization is received by ADL's transaction processing company.  

#### Surveys & Petitions

Our online surveys ask visitors for contact information (like their e-mail or mailing address). We use contact data from our surveys to send the user information about ADL and its activities. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section below. Other data collected by online surveys is used to educate ADL about the interests and concerns of its supporters and general site visitors concerning ADL's mission. This information is not shared with other organizations. ADL may operate e-mail discussions, and utilize contact lists to reach its members who request such information. Such services may be run both by ADL and contracted vendors. These e-mail addresses whether housed on ADL servers or those of a third-party contractor are never shared with any other organization and users may opt out of participating or receiving e-mail information from ADL at any time. Instructions are contained within each e-mail sent as well as on the help page of our Web site.

#### Sharing

We may share aggregated demographic information with our partners. This is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person.

We use an outside shipping company to ship orders, and a credit card processing company to bill users for goods and services. These companies are contractually prohibited from retaining, sharing, storing or using personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes.

We may partner with third parties to provide specific services. When a user signs up for these services, we will share names, or other contact information that is necessary for the third party to provide these services.

These parties are contractually prohibited from using personally identifiable information except for the purpose of providing these services.

We occasionally exchange or rent our contributor mailing lists with carefully selected organizations whose information we believe may be of interest to our donors.

Our ability to share your name with other charities or businesses will help us build our supporter base and expand our programs in a cost-effective way. If you prefer that we do not exchange or rent your name and postal address, please let us know by following the instructions in the opt-out procedures below.  

#### Tell a Friend

If a user elects to use our electronic mail referral service to inform a friend about our site, we collect the friend's name and e-mail address. ADL will automatically send the friend the e-mail and an invitation them to visit the site. ADL stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this introductory e-mail. The friend may write to ADL through our Contact Us form to request the removal of this information from our database.

#### Security

Our Web site has security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. This includes a firewall and 24 hour monitoring of site activities by our hosting service provider as well as 128-bit SSL encryption (where allowable by law) on all transaction oriented operations between you and ADL via our transaction service provider.

While we use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also do everything in our power to protect user-information off-line. All of our users' information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, our billing clerk, a customer service representative, or database administrator) are granted access to personally identifiable information. Every quarter, as well as any time new policies are added, our employees are notified and/or reminded about the importance we place on privacy, and what they are required to do to ensure our customers' information is protected. Finally, the servers that we use to store personally identifiable information on are kept in a secure environment.

#### Links to Other Sites

Occasionally, ADL's Web site may include links to other Web sites. ADL is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites.  

#### Correction/Updating Personal Information

If a user's personally identifiable information changes (such as your zip code), or if a user no longer desires our service, we will endeavor to provide a way to correct, update or remove that user's personal data provided to us. This can usually be done at the member information page or by writing to us through our Contact Us form.  

#### Choice/Opt Out Online & Offline

Our Web site provides users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us and our partners at the point where we request information about the visitor.

The following options are available for removing information from our database to discontinue receiving future communications or our service.

1\. You can unsubscribe or change your e-mail preferences online by following the link at the bottom of any e-mail you receive from ADL.

2\. You can notify us offline through the form on our Contact Us page of your desire to be removed from our e-mail list or contributor mailing list, or by contacting ADL's SVP of Privacy at privacy@adl.org or at ADL's mailing address: 605 Third Avenue, New York, NY 10158. 

#### Contacting the Website

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of our Web site or your dealings with the Web site, please send it to us through our Contact Us form.  

#### Notification of Changes

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes here so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and the circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users by way of an e-mail.  

**Anti-Defamation League**

605 Third Avenue

New York, NY 10158-3650

(212) 885.7700

Footer
------

Footer Social Links
-------------------

© 2024 Anti-Defamation League. All Rights Reserved.
